https://mainlinespine.com/privacy-policy/

Web privacy policy
We take your privacy seriously, and we want you to know how we collect, use, share and protect your information. In addition to this privacy policy, users of the Main Line Spine website should consult the Main Line Spine website Terms and Conditions of Use. We do not collect any patient information through the Main Line Spine website except that which you provide to us such as when requesting that we contact you to schedule an appointment.  We maintain separate policies specifically related to patient information (protected health information, or PHI) which is collected outside of the Main Line Spine website.
This policy applies to MainLineSpine.com and other web locations under Main Line Spine’s control.
What information we collect
We respect the right to privacy of all visitors to the Main Line Spine site. We do not collect information that would personally identify you unless you choose to provide it. For example, if you choose to contact us by using the form to Schedule an Appointment, this privacy policy and the terms and conditions of use apply. The personal information that you submit, such as on the appointment request form, is shared only with those people in the Main Line Spine organization who need this information to respond to your question or request and those internal areas that will utilize the information to improve Main Line Spine’s operations. Information submitted through Main Line Spine’s online forms may be collected to ensure technical functionality. It will also be utilized to address any inappropriate use of our website. We do not save personal information to use for other purposes, nor do we provide it to any other organizations.
Email communications, newsletter and related services
MainLineSpine.com provides you with the opportunity to receive communications from us or third parties. You can sign up for a free email newsletter. You can unsubscribe from this newsletter at any time.
Email communications that you send to us via the email links on our site may be shared with a patient service representative, employee, medical expert or agent that is most able to address your inquiry. We make every effort to respond in a timely fashion once communications are received. Once we have responded to your communication, it is discarded or archived, depending on the nature of the inquiry.
The email functionality on our site does not provide a completely secure and confidential means of communication. It’s possible that your email communication may be accessed or viewed by another Internet user while in transit to us. If you wish to keep your communication private, do not use our email.
You may decide at some point that you no longer wish to receive communications from our site. To stop receiving communications, send an email message to mainlinespine@comcast.net or send regular mail to the following postal address:
Practice Manager
Main Line Spine
700 S Henderson Rd, Suite #308-C
King of Prussia, PA 19406
Surveys
We occasionally survey visitors to our site. The information from these surveys is used in aggregated, de-identified form to help us understand the needs of our visitors so that we can improve our site. We generally do not ask for information in surveys that would personally identify you; if we do request contact information for follow-up, you may decline to provide it. If survey respondents provide personal information (such as an email address) in a survey, it is shared only with those people who need to see it to respond to the question or request, or with third parties who perform data management services for our site. Those third parties have agreed to keep all data from surveys confidential.
IP addresses
The Web server automatically collects the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computers that access our site. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you access the Internet. It is not truly personally identifiable information because many different individuals can access the Internet via the same computer. We use this information in aggregate form to understand how our site or advertisements from Main Line Spine are being used and how we can better serve visitors.
Cookies and other tracking technology
We collect information about visitors to our site using “cookies” (see definition on Webopedia) and similar technology such as Web beacons, Web bugs, pixel tags, and so on. We use this technology to recognize a repeat visitor and offer the visitor a set of services or information requested in a previous visit. We use session cookies to track a visitor’s path through our site during a visit, to help us understand how people use our site.
How we use the information we collect
We use the information we collect for things like:
Marketing and advertising products and services
Conducting research and analysis
Communicating things like special events and surveys
Identifying you on our website and tailoring advertisements and offers to you (both on our website and on other websites) based on your interactions with us online
Operating, evaluating and improving our practice
Data retention
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Except for authorized law enforcement investigations or other valid legal processes, we will not share any personally identifiable information we receive from you with any parties outside of Main Line Spine.
We may share some information to third parties
We may share your personally identifiable information with third parties who we have engaged to help us provide the services. In each case, we will ensure that these third parties have agreed not to use or disclose your personal information except to help us provide the services.
Except as noted above for newsletters and surveys, Main Line Spine does not provide any third party access to your IP address and email address.
We may provide third parties with aggregate statistics about our visitors, traffic patterns and related site information. These data reflect site-usage patterns gathered during visits to our website each month, but they do not contain behavioral or identifying information about any individual member unless that member has given us permission to share that information.
To help us determine the effectiveness of Main Line Spine advertising, we work with Web analytics tools hosted by third parties who receive nonidentifiable information from your browser, including but not limited to the site or the advertisement you came from, your IP address, your general geographic location, your browser and platform information, and the pages you view within our site.
Use of cookies by advertisers
Our sponsors and advertisers and their ad servers may use cookies when you view pages on our site. They use those cookies to collect nonpersonal information as a way of measuring the effectiveness of their advertising, or to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you or to avoid running the same ads to you over time. We do not control these third parties’ use of cookies or how they manage the nonpersonal information they gather through them. However, our sponsors and advertisers have agreed that they will not collect any personally identifiable information from our site visitors while they are on MainLineSpine.com. If you click on an advertisement on MainLineSpine.com and visit a site maintained by one of our sponsors or advertisers, please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of that site. You should read the privacy policies of each site you visit to determine what information that site may be collecting about you.
Some of our advertisers may participate in the Facebook/Nielsen program, which helps advertisers improve their measurement of advertising effectiveness. If you are a Facebook user and access a page on our site containing an ad from a participating advertiser, Facebook receives a random numeric code identifying the ad that was served to you. The ad is only identified to Facebook by the numeric code. Facebook does not receive information that identifies the product or the advertiser. Facebook, in turn, discloses only aggregate, de-identified information to Nielsen and the advertiser, not any personally identifiable information from your Facebook profile. You can learn more about this program and find out how to opt out here: https://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=211774365532736#What-is-the-Nielsen-partnership-with-Facebook-and-how-does-it-affect-me and here: http://www.nielsen-online.com/privacy.jsp?section=leg_scs.
Ads by Google
Note that Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our site users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. No personally identifiable information is collected as part of Google’s process. Users may opt out of the use of this DART cookie by visiting Google’s privacy document.
If you would like more information about these practices and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, visit the Network Advertising Initiative. Some ad servers allow you to opt out of anonymous data collection through the use of cookies. To do so, you must opt out of such data collection with each individual site. You can opt out of cookies for several ad servers by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative gateway opt-out site. At that site you can also review the privacy policies of those ad servers.
Protecting your privacy
When you visit the Main Line Spine website, we use reasonable security measures to protect the confidentiality of personal information under our control and appropriately limit access to it. We use a variety of information security measures to protect your online transactions with us. The Main Line Spine site uses encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), to protect your personal information during data transport. SSL protects information you submit via our website. That being said, Main Line Spine cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. We have taken reasonable steps to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of personally identifiable information that you may provide. You should understand, however, that electronic transmissions via the Internet are not necessarily secure from interception, and so we cannot absolutely guarantee the security or confidentiality of such transmissions.
To further protect your privacy, you may choose to:
Stop receiving newsletter emails from Main Line Spine
Update and correct your personal information
Cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services
To do any of these, contact Main Line Spine by one of the methods listed below.
If you reached this site via an ad from Main Line Spine
If you come to a Main Line Spine website via a Main Line Spine advertisement, the ad may have been served to you based on your interests or selected for you based on your browsing activities. If you want to opt out of being served Main Line Spine advertisements based on your browsing activity, you may opt out of cookies for multiple ad servers by visiting http://info.evidon.com/more_info/1936.
Protecting children’s privacy
We are committed to protecting children’s privacy on the Internet, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children.
Links to other websites
Our websites link to other websites, many of which have their own privacy policies. Be sure to review the privacy policy on the site you’re visiting.
Privacy policy updates
We may need to update our privacy policy as technology changes and Main Line Spine evolves. If we make significant changes to the privacy policy, we’ll post a prominent message on our websites.
Contact information
Practice Manager
Main Line Spine
700 S Henderson Rd, Suite #308-C
King of Prussia, PA 19406
If you’ve contacted the website about a privacy-related concern and you do not believe your problem has been addressed, you may file a complaint with the Main Line Spine Practice Manager by calling the Main Line Spine general number at (610) 337-3111 and asking for the practice manager.
Copy link
CopyCopied
Powered by Social Snap
